<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Fragment Fun</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="title_disclaimer">Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_text">Dear Colleague,\n\nThis tool provides decision-support information
        to assist you in managing Warfarin. I was taught that Warfarin is the single most dangerous
        medication in common use in all of medicine, and nothing in a dozen years of clinical practice
        has changed my opinion. Yet, Warfarin has the power to prevent great numbers of very serious
        events such as strokes pulmonary embolism. The stakes are high, so Warfarin care is serious work.
        \n\nInformation is published literature (see references). The author of the app has tried to faithfully
        present the guidance of others and not to substitute his own judgement.\n\nThis app is no substitute
        for knowledge, training, and experience in anti-coagulation. The app is merely a quick reference
        of reminders and updates on material you already know.\n\nAnd like any other general guide, these
        resources suggest how you might manage Warfarin for the average patient. But, this guide cannot
        tell you how to manage the single unique patient at hand right now. Be vigilant for over and under-use
        of Warfarin. Be vigilant for other changes in medical status which affect suitability or response
        to Warfarin therapy. Be vigilant for advances and changes in anti-coagulation care. Individualize your
        care. And most of all, do your own thinking.</string>
    <string name="DVTorPE"> Proximal CVT of leg provoked by surgery \n- target 2.0-3.0 \n- duration 3 months \n\nProximal DVT of leg provoked by
        nonsurgical transient risk factor \n- target 2.0-3.0 \n- duration 3 months if high bleeding risk* \n- duration indefinitely if low-to-moderate
    bleeding risk* \n\nDistal isolated DVT of leg without severe symptoms or risk factors for extension \n-serial imaging of deep veins to eval for
    extension rather than coagulation \n- if extends, anti-coagulate as below \nDistal isolated DVT of leg with severe symptoms or risk factors for
    extension \n- target 2.0-3.0 \n- duration 3 months \n- then evaluate for risk-benefit balance of indefinitely further anti-coagulation with
    preference for cessation \nDistal isolated DVT of leg provoked by surgery or nonsurgical transient risk factor in whom anti-coagulation is elected
        \n- target 2.0-3.0 \n- duration 3 months</string>
</resources>
