<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Fragment Fun</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">References</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">About App</string>
    <string name="title_disclaimer">Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_text">Dear Colleague,\n\nThis tool provides decision-support information
        to assist you in managing Warfarin. I was taught that Warfarin is the single most dangerous
        medication in common use in all of medicine, and nothing in a dozen years of clinical practice
        has changed my opinion. Yet, Warfarin has the power to prevent great numbers of very serious
        events such as strokes pulmonary embolism. The stakes are high, so Warfarin care is serious work.
        \n\nInformation is published literature (see references). The author of the app has tried to faithfully
        present the guidance of others and not to substitute his own judgement.\n\nThis app is no substitute
        for knowledge, training, and experience in anti-coagulation. The app is merely a quick reference
        of reminders and updates on material you already know.\n\nAnd like any other general guide, these
        resources suggest how you might manage Warfarin for the average patient. But, this guide cannot
        tell you how to manage the single unique patient at hand right now. Be vigilant for over and under-use
        of Warfarin. Be vigilant for other changes in medical status which affect suitability or response
        to Warfarin therapy. Be vigilant for advances and changes in anti-coagulation care. Individualize your
        care. And most of all, do your own thinking.</string>
    <string name="references_text">Ansell J., et. al., \'Pharmacology and Management of the Vitamin K Antagonists.
        Antithrombotic and Thrombolytic Therapy: American College of Chest Physicians Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guidelines
        (8th Edition)\'. Chest, vol. 133, no. 6; supplement pg. 160S-198S, June 2008. Available at www.chestjournal.org\n
        \nEbell, M, \'Point of Care Guides: Evidence-Based Adjustment of Warfarin (Coumadin) Doses\'.
        American Family Physician, vol. 71, no. 10, pg. 1979-1982, May 15, 2005. Available at www.aafp.org\n
        \nEbell, M, \'Point of Care Guides: Evidence-based Initiation of Warfarin (Coumadin)\'. American Family Physician,
        vol. 71, no. 4, pg. 763-765, February 15, 2005. Available at www.aafp.org\n
        \nKearon C., et. al., \'Antithrombotic Therapy for Venous Thromboembolic Disease. Antithrombotic and Thrombolytic
        Therapy: American College of Chest Physicians Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guidelines (8th Edition)\'. Chest,
        vol. 133, no. 6; supplement pg. 454S-545S, June 2008. Available at www.chestjournal.org\n
        \nSalem N., et. al., \'Valvular and Structural Heart Disease. Antithrombotic and Thrombolytic Therapy:
        American College of Chest Physicians Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guidelines (8th Edition)\'. Chest, vol.
        133, no. 6; supplement pg. 593S-629S, June 2008.  Available at www.chestjournal.org\n
        \nSinger D., et. al., \'Antithrombotic Therapy in Atrial Fibrillation. Antithrombotic and Thrombolytic Therapy:
        American College of Chest Physicians Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guidelines (8th Edition)\'. Chest, vol. 133, no. 6;
        supplement pg. 546S-592S, June 2008.  Available at www.chestjournal.org</string>
    <string name="about_protocol">ACCP 2012 guideline reports evidence of benefit from use of decision-support
        tools to guide maintenance of Warfarin therapy, particularly for inexperienced prescribers.
        But the guideline does not compare or endorse any particular dosage management schemes. Thus
        this app continues with the same Warfarin adjustment scheme from the family medicine literature
        with only slight modifications to accommodate the new recommendation about single mildly out-of-range INR results.\n
        \nThe other emphasis made by ACCP regarding approach to anticoagulation management is that it should be done in a
        systematic and coordinated fashion, incorporating patient education, systematic INR testing, tracking, follow-up,
        and good patient communication of results and dosing decisions. This includes, notably, the option of patient
        self-testing and self-management for those select patients who demonstrate motivation and competency in self-management
        tools and strategies.</string>
    <string name="initiate">It is difficult to predict how much Warfarin a patient will ultimately need for daily or weekly dosing.
        So the approach is to get dosing started, make initial adjustments, get the patient close enough to therapeutic so that
        any coadministered heparin can be stopped, and transition from initiation to maintenance of Warfarin.\n\nSeveral
        schemes have been reported in the literature aiming to achieve therapeutic INR level rapidly and safely.
        They either start with 5 mg daily or 10 mg daily and then offer algorithms for dose adjustment after
        a couple days of therapy onward. Looking at almost the identical literature set, the AFP 2005 review
        concludes that both the 5 mg and 10 mg initiation schemes are reasonable, while the ACCP 2012 review
        expresses preference for the 10 mg schemes. The AFP article offers the actual details of several
        initiation schemes themselves so that you can implement the one you decide is appropriate for your patient.\n\nIf
        your humble writer and amateur programmer acquires the skill, I\'ll include the various initiation protocols
        for ease of use in this app in the future.\n\nThe
        other issue ACCP 2012 addresses is the recent emergence of Warfarin initiation based on pharmacogenetic testing.
        Their discussion of the evidence to date leads ACCP to recommend against routine use of pharmacogenetic
        testing for guiding doses of Warfarin.</string>
    <string name="alert">This app presents the Point-of-Care Guides on the use of Warfarin (Coumadin) from the
        family medicine literature, updated for the 2008 and 2012 ACCP guidelines on antithrombotic therapy.
        It contains guidance on indications, INR targets, treatment duration, initiation, and adjustment protocols.</string>
    <string name="periop_mgmt">The management of Warfarin before, during, and after surgery depends greatly on
        the type of surgery and the risk of a thromboembolic event were anticoagulation to be suspended temporarily.\n
        For detailed guidance on this topic, please see our free app in the iTunes App Store, &quot;Preop Eval &apos;14&quot;.</string>
    <string name="afib_flutter">Acute A-Fib/Flutter ≥ 48 hrs or unknown duration and cardioversion planned:
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 wks before cardioversion
        \n- duration pre-cardioversion can be truncated if high-quality TEE reassures against atrial thrombus
        \n- duration 4+ wks after cardioversion
        \n- whether to anticoagulate after 4 wks has no evidence to guide therapy. Many pts 1 year out from seemingly
        successful cardioversion are back in A-fib.  Thus ACCP recommends individual risk assessment based on CHADS2
        stroke risk, bleeding risk, and other pt specific factors for this decision\n
        \nAcute A-Fib/Flutter known duration \u003C 48 hrs and cardioversion planned:
        \n- IV Heparin or LMWH recommended at presentation if no contraindication present
        \n- after successful cardioversion anti-coagulate (Warfarin, LMWH, newer agents) at least 4 weeks
        \n- consider longterm anticoagulation after initial 4 weeks based upon individual pt risks as described
        above for A-fib ≥ 48 hrs\n
        \nChronic Atrial Fibrillation, Paroxysmal A-Fib, and A-Flutter:
        \n- first do CHADS2 score for longterm risk of ischemic stroke:\n
        \nC (CHF or mod-sev LV dysfxn, 1 pt),
        \nH (hypertension, 1 pt),
        \nA (age ≥ 75 yrs, 1 pt),
        \nD (diabetes, 1 pt),
        \nS (prior stroke, TIA, or systemic embolic event, 2 pts)\n
        \nCHADS2 ≥ 2:
        \n- rec Warfarin over antiplatelet therapy
        \n- Aspirin 75-325 mg \u0026 Clopidogrel 75 mg for those unsuitable or choose not to take Warfarin (for reasons
        other than major bleeding concerns)\n
        \nCHADS2 = 1:
        \n- rec Warfarin over no therapy
        \n- Warfarin preferred over antiplatelet therapy
        \n- Aspirin 75-325 mg \u0026 Clopidogrel 75 mg for those unsuitable or choose not to take Warfarin (for reasons
        other than major bleeding concerns)\n
        \nCHADS2 = 0:
        \n- rec no therapy over any therapy
        \n- for those who choose therapy, aspirin 75-325 mg preferred over Warfarin and over aspirin \u0026 clopidogrel
        \n- target INR 2.0-3.0 for Warfarin use
        \n- duration indefinitely\n
        \nNote: In some atrial fibrillation patients, the risk of major bleeding may be as great or greater than the
        risk of a thromboembolic event. In some cases, your knowledge of the patient may be sufficient to make this
        judgment (i.e. frequent falls, inability to comply with careful use of medication). For a quantitative
        consideration of risk of embolic event versus risk of major bleeding event, consult risk estimation tools
        such as CHADS2 for risk of stroke from A-fib and OBRI for risk of major bleeding. There are several point-of-care
        calculators to make these estimates, one that I use is Calculate by QxMD software.
        Notably, the 2012 ACCP A-fib guideline endorses consideration of individual patient characteristics
        like bleeding risk when considering whether to anticoagulate, while the 2012 ACCP Evidence-Based Mgmt
        of Anticoagulant Therapy guideline cautions not to use bleeding risk tools as the sole criterion to
        withhold anticoagulation.</string>
    <string name="dvt_or_pe">Proximal DVT of leg provoked by surgery
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months\n
        \nProximal DVT of leg provoked by nonsurgical transient risk factor
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months if high bleeding risk*
        \n- duration indefinitely if low-to-moderate bleding risk*\n
        \nDistal isolated DVT of leg without severe symptoms or risk factors for extension
        \n- serial imaging of deep veins to eval for extension rather than anti-coagulation
        \n- if extends, anticoagulate as below\n
        \nDistal isolated DVT of leg with severe symptoms or risk factors for extension
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n- then evaluate for risk-benefit balance of indefinitely further anticoagulation with preference for cessation\n
        \nDistal isolated DVT of leg provoked by surgery or nonsurgical transient risk factor in whom anticoagulation is elected
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months\n
        \nUnprovoked DVT of leg (including all proximal and those distal clots treated with anticoagulation)
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n- then consider those at low-to-moderate bleeding risk* for indefinite further anticoagulation and those at high bleeding risk* for cessation\n
        \nPatients with second unprovoked VTE (DVT or PE)
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months for those with high bleeding risk*
        \n- duration indefinitely for those with low-to-moderate bleeding risk*\n
        \nDVT and active cancer
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration indefinitely\n
        \nPE provoked by surgery
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months\n
        \nPE provoked by a nonsurgical transient risk factor
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months\n
        \nPE unprovoked
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n- then consider those at low-to-moderate bleeding risk* for indefinite further anticoagulation and those at high bleeding risk* for cessation\n
        \nPE and active cancer
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration indefinitely\n
        \nPatients incidentally found to have asymptomatic DVT or PE
        \n- same mgmt as comparable pts with symptomatic DVT or PE\n
        \nSVT (superficial vein thrombosis) leg 5+ cm long
        \n- prophylactic dose fondaparinux preferred over LMWH
        \n- duration 45 days\n
        \nUEDVT (upper extr DVT) associated with central venous catheter
        \n- catheter need not be removed if functional and valuable for pt care\n
        \nUEDVT assoc with central venous catheter which is not removed
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration as long as catheter remains\n
        \nUEDVT assoc with catheter which is removed
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months\n
        \nUEDVT not assoc with catheter
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months\n
        \nPatients with symptomatic hepatic or splanchnic vein thrombosis (portal, mesenteric, and/or splenic)
        \n- anticoagulation recommended, preference for LMWH over Warfarin if active cancer, liver disease, thrombocytopenia
        \n- duration indefinitely if no transient risk factor and low risk of bleeding, 3 months preferred otherwise\n
        \nPatients with asymptomatic hepatic or splanchnic vein thrombosis
        \n- no anticoagulation recommended
        \n- data to guide this situation sparse\n
        \n* Bleeding risk scheme:
        \nLow risk = 0 risk factors
        \nModerate risk = 1 risk factor
        \nHigh risk = 2+ risk factors
        \nRisk factors: age > 65, previous bleed, cancer, renal failure, liver failure, thrombocytopenia,
        previous stroke, diabetes, anemia, antiplatelet therapy, poor anticoagulant control, comorbidity
        and reduced functional capacity, recent surgery, frequent falls, alcohol use
        </string>
    <string name="valve_structural" formatted="false">Rheumatic mitral valve dz, normal sinus rhythm, and left atrial diameter \u003C 55 mm
        \n- no anticoagulant or antiplatelet recommended
        \n\nRheumatic mitral valve dz, normal sinus rhythm, and left atrial diameter > 55 mm
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration indefinitely
        \n\nRheumatic mitral valve dz complicated singly or in combination by A-Fib, left atrial thrombus, or previous systemic embolism
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration indefinitely
        \n\nWhen percutaneous mitral balloon valvulotomy (PMBV) considered and TEE shows left atrial thrombus
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration until thrombus resolves
        \n\nPatent Foramen Ovale (PFO) or atrial septal aneurysm asymptomatic
        \n- no anticoagulant recommended
        \n\nPFO or atrial septal aneurysm with cryptogenic stroke
        \n- aspirin therapy recommended
        \n\nPFO or atrial septal aneurysm with recurrent cryptogenic stroke events despite aspirin
        \n- target INR 2.0-3.0
        \n- consider device closure over aspirin
        \n\nPFO, cryptogenic stroke, and evidence of DVT
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n- consider device closure over no Warfarin or no aspirin therapy
        \n\nInfective endocarditis without another particular indication
        \n- no anticoagulant or antiplatelet recommended
        \n\nAortic bioprosthetic valve with sinus rhythm and no other Warfarin indication
        \n- aspirin 50-100 mg/day
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n\nTranscatheter aortic bioprosthetic valve
        \n- aspirin 50-100 mg/day \u0026 clopidogrel 75 mg/day
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n\nMitral bioprosthetic valve
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration 3 months
        \n\nBioprosthetic valve in any position after first 3 months post-insertion
        \n- aspirin
        \n- duration indefinite
        \n\nMechanical aortic valve
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- consider adding aspirin 50-100 mg/day for pts at low risk of bleeding
        \n- duration indefinite
        \n\nMechanical mitral valve
        \n- target 2.5-3.5
        \n- consider adding aspirin 50-100 mg/day for pts at low risk of bleeding
        \n- duration indefinite
        \n\nMechanical valve in aortic and mitral position
        \n- target 2.5-3.5
        \n- consider adding aspirin 50-100 mg/day for pts at low risk of bleeding
        \n- duration indefnite
        \n\nAnterior myocardial infarction (MI) and left ventricular (LV) thrombus or at high risk for LV thrombus (EF &lt; 40&#37;,
        anteroseptal wall motion abnormality) who do not receive stent
        \n- target 2.0-3.0 plus aspirin 75-100 mg/day
        \n- duration first 3 mos
        \n- dual antiplatelet therapy alone months 3-12
        \n- single antiplatelet therapy after 12 months
        \n\nAnterior MI and LV thrombus or at high risk for LV thrombus (EF &lt; 40&#37;, anteroseptal wall motion abnormality)
        who receive bare metal stent (BMS)
        \n- target 2.0-3.0 plus low-dose aspirin and clopidogrel 75 mg/day
        \n- duration 1st month
        \n- target INR 2.0-3.0 plus single antiplatelet therapy 2nd &amp; 3rd month
        \n- dual antiplatelet therapy alone months 4-12
        \n- standard antiplatelet therapy after 12 months
        \n\nAnterior MI and LV thrombus or at high risk for LV thrombus (EF &lt; 40&#37;, anteroseptal wall motion abnormality)
        who receive drug-eluting stent (DES)
        \n- target 2.0-3.0 plus low-dose aspirin and clopidogrel 75 mg/day
        \n- duration 3-6 months
        \n- dual antiplatelet therapy alone thru 12 months
        \n- standard antiplatelet therapy after 12 months
        \n\nSystolic LV dysfunction with acute LV thrombus but without established CAD
        \n- target 2.0-3.0
        \n- duration at least 3 months</string>
    <string name="ortho_surgery">Major orthopedic surgery (total hip, total knee, hip fracture)
        pts should receive an antithrombotic prophylactic with one of following agents
        \n- LMWH (low molecular wt heparin), fondaparinux, apixaban, dabigatran, rivaroxaban, LDUH (low dose
        unfractionated heparin), VKA (Warfarin), aspirin (debatable, see article), or intermittant pneumatic
        compression device (IPCD)
        \n- preference for LMWH over others
        \n- duration minimum 10-14 days post-op
        \n- duration preferred extended up to 35 days
        \n\nDual prophylaxis with antithrombotic agent and IPCD recommended during hospital stay
        \n- guideline quite specific about features of IPCD necessary to confer benefit
        \n\nPatients with an increased risk of bleeding receive recommendation for IPCD or no prophylaxis over pharmacologic agent
        \n- bleeding risk factors are (1) previous major bleeding without change for risk of recurrence, (2) severe renal
        failure, (3) concomitant antiplatelet agent, (4)surgical factors: history of or difficult-to-control surgical
        bleeding during the current operative procedure, extensive surgical dissection, revision surgery
        \n- absolute risks of bleeding on pharmacologic agents are small
        \n- balance of risks, benefits, and preferences should be individualized to the pt
        \n\nMajor orthopedic surgery pts who decline or are uncooperative with injections or an IPCD
        \n- apixaban or dabigatran recommended
        \n- rivaroxaban or VKA (Warfarin) if above unavailable
        \n\nPatients with just knee arthroscopy without history of VTE
        \n- no prophylaxis recommended
        \n\nPatients with isolated lower-leg injuries requiring leg immobilization
        \n- no prophylaxis recommended</string>
    <string name="thrombophilia">ACCP 2012 guideline recommends in patients with asymptomatic thrombophilia
        (that is, no history of previous VTE) not to use mechanical or pharmacologic thrombo-prophylaxis.
        \n\nThere is very little evidence to provide guidance on this topic, and even less of quality.
        \n\nFor those patients who have had a VTE event in setting of thrombophilia, anticoagulation is recommended
        \n- target 2.0-3.0, even for antiphos
        \n-pholipid syndrome pts
        \n- duration indefinitely</string>
    <string name="major_bleed">Patient has major bleeding at any INR level:
        \n\n2012 edition: rapidly reverse Warfarin anticoagulation with four-factor prothrombin complex
        concentrate (PCC), fresh frozen plasma (FFP), or recombinant factor VIIa, with preference for PCC over FFP.
        Additionally, give Vit K 5-10 mg slow IV push, as the benefit of the above coagulation factor(s) is relatively
        short-lived compared to the Warfarin still in the pt.
        \n\nPrevious editions broke up the guidance into two categories of bleeding: serious and life-threatening.
        \n\n- Serious bleeding: hold all Warfarin therapy, give Vit K 10 mg slow IV push plus fresh frozen plasma
        (FFP) or pro-thrombin complex concentrate depending upon urgency, repeat Vit K every 12 hours as needed.
        \n\n- Life-threatening bleeding: hold all Warfarin therapy, give prothrombin complex concentrate
        (or recombinant factor VIIa as an alternative) supplemented with Vit K 10 mg slow IV push, repeat as needed.</string>
    <string name="gt_10_no_sig_bleeding">Result of INR is > 10.0 and there is no significant bleeding:
        \n\n2012 edition: recommends giving Vit K, no other explicit guidance. Discussion cites doses of 2-2.5 mg oral
        Vit K used in studies but does not cite whether this is an optimal dose.
        \n\nPrevious editions: hold all Warfarin therapy, give Vit K 5-10 mg orally, monitor INR frequently,
        and resume Warfarin at lower dose when INR is therapeutic. (Note that the INR level for this guidance
        in previous editions was 8.9, not 10.0)</string>
    <string name="lte_10_no_sig_bleeding">Result of INR is ≤ 10.0 and there is no significant bleeding:
        \n\n2012 edition: recommends against Vit K, no other explicit guidance
        \n\nPrevious editions: hold dose for 1-2 days, consider Vit K 1-2.5 mg orally, decrease total weekly
        dose by 10% to 20%, and monitor INR frequently.  (Note that the INR level for this guidance in previous editions was 8.9, not 10.0)</string>
    <string name="adjust_note">NOTE: Always ask questions and think before adjusting Warfarin dosing.
        \n- When was the last INR? the last dose change?
        \n- Did pt make last recommended dose change, and when?
        \n- Does this INR reflect steady state?
        \n- Does non-therapeutic INR reflect incorrect dose, incorrect dosing directions [i.e. miscommunication], new medication
        or medical condition, or non-compliance?</string>
    <string name="inr_lt_1_5">Result of INR is &lt; 1.5 *
        \nIncrease total weekly dose by 10% to 20%, consider extra dose
        \n\nNext INR:
        \n4 to 8 days
        \n\n* before you change dose, assess patient compliance &#8212; maybe dose is right but patient isn\'t taking it</string>
    <string name="elevated_inr_note">The ACCP 2012 guideline recommendations for elevated INR\'s are less
        interventional than previous but also less clear.  E.g. for elevated INR without bleeding we are
        told what action should not be taken (no Vit K), but are not told what action should be taken.
        For familiarity and clarity, new recommendations will be presented along with the old.</string>
</resources>
